Have you ever wondered how apps like this one are making $500,000 every single month?
Well, what if I told you that I just built an exact copy of this million dollar app without
writing a single line of code? Now, I can hear you thinking already, but if you check out the
screenshot, you can see proof of the revenue that this type of app generates through the app store.
Half a million dollars every month, and here's a crazier part I used only one AI tool to build the
entire thing. Now, most people think that you need years of coding experience or a whole team of
developers to create profitable apps, but that's completely wrong. I'm about to show you the exact
step-by-step process that I use to recreate this successful workout tracking app, connect it to
Stripe for payments, and set up all of the premium features without touching a single line of code.
By the way, my name is Mikey, and my K-E-Y, and I've been experimenting with AI development tools
for the past year, and what I discovered is that there's one AI coding tool right now that's
absolutely crushing everything else, and it can literally build entire apps for you. In this video,
I'm going to walk you through my complete process. I'm going to show you the exact tool that I used,
and I'm going to prove that anyone you, me, even complete beginners, can build profitable apps in
2025. So, if you've ever wanted to create your own app, or make money from app development, or
we're just super curious about what's possible with AI right now, this video I promise you
is going to blow your mind. So, let's go ahead and dive right in. The AI tool that will take care of
everything for us today in this video will be Rocket.New. I added a special link in the description below,
so you can go ahead and check it out for yourself too. So, whenever I'm starting with a new app
build, the very first thing that I want to do is get a layout down. Something that shows you how
everything will be structured before we begin layering in features. It's pretty much like sketching
the blueprint of a house before deciding on the furniture. Now, this first step will give us a
clear picture of how the app will flow, and it'll also set the foundation for everything we're
going to add in later. So, for this build, again, we'll be using Rocket, and one of the biggest
advantages here of using Rocket is code ownership. Unlike other platforms that lock you in,
you own your own code completely. You can download it, you can modify it, you can post it anywhere
you want, even if you cancel your subscription, your apps, and your code remain yours forever.
All right, so here's what we're going to tell Rocket. Hey Rocket, let's build an awesome
mobile fitness app. First, please build the UI of the app, then we'll add some features
afterwards. Please build all the sections and the nav bar needed. All right, before we move on,
important disclaimer here, because building apps and making money online is not easy, despite
what other YouTubers might be saying. So, when I show you how to build an app, for example,
I'm demonstrating the technical process and the potential. I am not guaranteeing your results.
These AI tools are legit, and as you'll see, the techniques do work, but success as with all
things in life depends on your execution, your timing, and honestly some luck. Now most apps don't
make money right away, and many don't even make money at all. So, I'm not promising you're going
to get rich or that you go out and quit your job after this video. Now, this is not financial advice,
or a get rich quick scheme. I'm just showing you what's possible with these tools, and what you do
that knowledge is up to you. All right, so with those expectations set, let's go ahead and continue
building this app. So, Rocket responds by putting together a clean, elegant design for our fitness app.
All the major sections are there, the placeholders are neatly set, and the overall look already
feels polished even at this early stage. It is simple, but it gives us a working canvas that we
can start refining right away. So, let's go ahead and look through the app, and you can see here that
the structure is functional, but there is a small error. The nav bar doesn't appear on the home screen,
which might make the navigation look incomplete at first. But if I do tap into one of the sections,
the nav bar appears, and it works as expected. So, it is a promising start, but in the next step,
we'll make sure that the nav bar shows up everywhere so that our navigation feels seamless from
the very beginning. Now that we've got the basic layout in place, we are now going to go ahead and
take things up a notch. Now, the first version gave us a solid foundation, but the design still feels
pretty bare bones to me, and that nav bar isn't showing up consistently across our app. So,
what I want next is a cleaner, more modern look that works like a proper fitness app, and of course,
a fully working nav bar that ties the whole experience together. So, to accomplish all of that,
here's what we're going to ask Rocket, great job Rocket. Now, please improve the app's design,
give it a modern exercise look, and add a nav bar, and the other sections we may need focus on this
first, then we'll build more functionality later. And Rocket comes back with a much more polished
design. As you can see, the layout has been updated to look like a real exercise app, it's modern,
it's cohesive, and it's visually appealing. On top of all of that, we now have a responsive nav bar
that shows up consistently, which does let us move smoothly between different sections. Now,
another cool thing here is that Rocket just doesn't design scratch. Say, you already have a mock-up
sitting in Figma. Well, we can upload that directly into Rocket, and it will turn it into production
ready code with pixel-perfect accuracy. And that means no messy hand-offs to other developers,
and no, it doesn't manage the design kind of frustrations. Because your app looks exactly how you
imagined it and designed it. And speaking of design, you can see the difference here, right away,
and this updated build, these sections are more connected, the design flows better, and that nav
bar ties everything together in a way that makes navigation seamless. Now, this upgrade gives us the
confidence to move forward, knowing that our app doesn't just work structurally, but also looks the
part. Okay, so a fitness app without a workout tracker doesn't really make my sense. So this is where
we start building out the core functionality. And the goal here is to let our users create their
own workouts, track their own progress, and have that flexibility to manage sessions, however they
want. So let's make that happen by sending Rocket this kind of prompt. Great job Rocket. Let's focus
on building the actual functionality. Please create a workout tracker and a creator feature,
where the user can create their own custom workouts and track their progress in set workouts.
Give them the ability to add notes and progress photos in the workout plans they created. Also,
give them the ability to add exercises or sets while a workout they created is in progress.
Lastly, give them the ability to be able to finish workouts that they started at any time without
completing all the exercises. And now the workflow delivers a fully functional workout tracker
inside of our app. And our users can now design custom workout plans. They can attach notes,
they can include their own progress photos and add or remove sets as they go. And one of the best
parts is that workouts they don't have to be fully completed to a session. And this gives our
users more realistic control over how they train. Okay, so let's go ahead and try all of that out.
I'll create a workout called say calspanics and I'm going to start adding exercises. So first,
I'll add some push-ups and then some planks. But I'm also going to go ahead and try to delete the
planks. And there you go, the delete button works. And if something ever doesn't work as expected,
Rocket's built-in error detection will spot it and then offers a one-click fix. So instead of
having to dig through a bunch of code, we can just hit fix it and then move on. And after checking
that, I'll follow it up with some burpees. I'll save the workouts and then now I'm going to activate
it. From here, the app lets me run the workout. And if I decide to finish early, I can go ahead and
close it out without needing to complete a real asset. So it's flexible, it's practical, and it
feels like a real fitness tracker that adapts to our users. Every good fitness app needs a knowledge
base that users can rely on not just for tracking their own workouts, but also for guidance and
for ideas. Right now, the library section in our app has just been placeholder. So it's now time
to turn that into a real resource. And this means giving our users access to a complete workout
database filled with details and instructions that they can use at any time. So here's the prompt
we're going to send over to Rocket to make that all happen. Awesome job Rocket. Now please build the
workout library slash database, create a thorough database with instructions and details for several
workouts ranging from cardio, weightlifting, calisthenics, and body weight and the like. And with that,
Rocket built out a full workout library inside of our app. And now instead of empty place folders,
that section is now populated with a variety of exercises across different categories. And each
entry comes with clear instructions and details so that our users can follow along and incorporate
new routines into their own training. Doing this transforms the library into more than just a
section of the app. It's now a built in guide to help our users reach their fitness goals.
Alright, let's go ahead and explore this new database. So I'm going to head into the library here
and I'm going to start scrolling through some of the options that unlike before or everything just
kind of looked empty and unfinished. This section as you can see now holds real content. And look what I
said earlier, the workout entry now includes instructions and details which makes our app much more
complete and gives our users a reliable source of reference whenever they need or want to try
something new in their programming. We all know that workouts are great on their own but many people
do prefer following structured programs that lay out routines week by week. So for this next
step, I want to expand our library into something bigger, not just individual workouts but full-on
training programs like starting strength and strong lifts five by five. This will give users a clear
roadmap complete with principles and progression instead of just leaving them to piece things together
and to do that all it takes is this prop and rocket will handle the rest for us. Awesome job
rocket. Now please expand our application by creating optimized programs in our workout library.
Please create optimized programs such as starting strength, strong lifts, five by five and the
like. And from that problem, we get an expanded program library right inside of our app. So instead of
just exercises, we now have full-fledged programs that break down training into steps, routines,
and guiding principles. And these programs provide structure for anyone who wants to prove in
system to follow like five by five and they even include the extra details like nutrition advice
to keep the experience well rounded. All right, so check this out. We can see here under the
new program section, a full list of structured training plans is ready to explore and opening them
up reveals complete routines, clear principles, and supporting details that go beyond just exercises.
Even touching on nutrition, now compared to where we started off in this video, this addition
turns our app into a guide that can now carry our users through an entire fitness journey all step
by step. Now after all that building and refining, I think it's now finally time to step back and
see how everything comes together. So I'm going to walk you through the app section by section.
Now here, each part looks complete and it's all connected now seamlessly. Our app no longer is just
a collection of features, but it is a cohesive fitness platform. So let's put the workout creator
to the test. I'll go into the workout section here. I'm going to start building a new routine. I'll
also add a mix of different exercises. I'll save the plan and then I'm just going to launch it.
And while running the workout, I am going to drop in some personal notes of mine and even upload a
progress photo to show how flexible the feature really is. And just like we designed earlier,
I'm able to finish the workout early without having to complete every exercise. Now let's go ahead
and move into the program library to check out the specialized training programs that we recently
added. And there you go. It is a library, a planner and a workout companion, all at one place.
Now by this point, I'm hoping that we can all agree this doesn't feel just like a prototype
anymore. Because while other platforms struggle to make mobile apps actually work, rocket generates
real flutter apps that run seamlessly across both iOS and Android with true native performance.
And on top of that, it gives you a ready-made frame on the back end. So you can choose whether to
build a web app, a mobile app, or even an internal tool. Okay, so now that we've seen how the app
functions as a whole, it's time to add another feature because why not? That makes workouts more
practical in real life. And one feature that every fitness app needs is a reliable timer because
I don't want to open another app. So whether it's for rest periods, circuit training, or just
keeping workout structured, having a timer built directly into the dashboard makes the whole
experience more seamless. And to do that, we'll guide rocket with this prompt to get the feature
built in. Awesome. Now please create a timer in the home and dashboard. This should be at the front.
Make the default time as two minutes, which can be customized and edited manually. Also,
below the timer have a selection from our existing workouts that the user can tap. So the timer
starts automatically displaying the workout. Okay, so the output for that gives us a dedicated timer
right here on our dashboard. It isn't just a standalone tool either. It also doubles as a quick
start option for any workout that we choose since all the routines we've created are listed right
below it. And that way we can jump straight into training without any extra steps. So to showcase
this, I'm going to go ahead and run through a quick test. I'll adjust the timer settings here
by changing the minutes. I'm also going to try out the reset, start, and stop buttons just to make
sure everything works smoothly. And after that, I'm just going to go ahead and pick one of the workouts
from the mile workout section. And just like we planned, the timer automatically starts with that
routine that I just chose. Now, so when it comes to fitness, right, fitness apps, nothing's more
motivating than actually seeing your own progress. And that's why the final piece we're adding is a
proper progress tracker, something that goes beyond just logging workouts and really shows us how far
we've come. So I'm going to ask Rocket to build out a full progress section stats, body measurements,
and photo tracking to tie everything together, something like this. Great job Rocket. Now let's focus
on building the progress tracking feature and statistics. Please build the progress section and
allow the user to track their progress with advanced statistics that show personal records and
progression. Also add a body measurements tracker for weight and vitals and give the ability to
upload and add photos of the user's progress. And the output for that shows that the app now has a
working progress tracking section and everything inside of it is functional and it is ready to use.
So let's go ahead and try to upload a simple progress photo, then track my weight and body part
measurements here. And instantly the analytics will pop up showing clear stats and progression trends.
It's surprisingly satisfying to watch the numbers and the visuals all line up and it's all
proof that the workouts and routines are paying off. At this point the app has plenty of features
but without accounts and authentication it really is just a single user experience. So in order to
make it feel like a complete platform our next step is to hook it up with Superbase and add proper
login and sign up pages. The setup starts by heading over to my Superbase here, creating a new
project then going into the integration panel back in rocket and then just linking that project
into our app. And once that's ready here's the prompt we'll use. Now please integrate Superbase
and create the login and sign up pages. Also make sure that the profile section shows the logged in
user. And with that rocket takes care of the integration and generates a clean authentication flow.
We now have dedicated login and sign up screens along with user account handling powered by Superbase.
And along with that the app automatically pulls in profile information so that our logged in
user's name shows up right here on the dashboard and in the profile section. And this isn't just a
demo either because when rocket adds Superbase authentication or later on strike payments it is
production ready functionality. It's not placeholder code. So you can connect your accounts and then
start processing real logins or payments right away. And with that let's go ahead and test all of
that out. I'm going to create a fresh account here. I'm going to sign in and I'm going to move
into the app and everything so far works smoothly. The sign up goes through the login directs me
straight to my dashboard and my name displays exactly where it should. All right so far we've built
a ton of features tracking and authentication but to really turn this into a business we need a way
to monetize it and we'll be needing stripe here and the idea here is simple which is to give users a
smooth upgrade path so that they can unlock everything that our app has to offer. And to do that
I'm going to head over to my stripe. I'm going to grab the publishable and secret keys and then
I'm simply going to plug them into rockets integration panel under the stripe section. And after
setting that up I'm just going to drop in this final prompt. Great job rocket. Now lastly please
integrate stripe and have a simple checkout link using the keys that I provided. Please create a
new section called upgrade and within that section show the details and benefits of our apps premium
upgrade at the bottom of the section. We have a checkout button which redirects to stripe and with
that prompt rocket instantly adds an upgrade tab to our app right here and inside users can see
exactly what premium offers. Advanced tracking, expanded features and all the little extras that we
added earlier that set it apart. There's also a checkout button that connects directly to stripe.
So subscribing really just takes one click and once the subscription goes through the app confirms
the account is premium and then it unlocks all of that good gated content. All right so now I'm
going to try and see if all of this works out. So let's navigate to the new upgrade section here.
Let's go ahead and review the benefits. Let's hit checkout and now complete a test subscription.
And right after that as you can see the dashboard updates with a premium status. No hiccups, no confusion.
And now that stripe is in place the app officially has everything it needs to not just support our
users but also sustain itself as a real product. And for the final run through I'm going to go ahead
and start things off by creating a brand new account. Say calling it fit rocket because why not.
And after signing in I'll move to the app the way any user would checking out each section as if
I'm using it for the first time. Now here in the workouts tab I'm going to put together a custom
routine. I'm going to add a few personal notes and I'll upload a quick progress photo before
finishing the session to show how flexible the feature is. And after that I'm going to head over to
the timer here and I'm going to play around with it setting it to say 10 minutes just to test how
smooth it feels. Then I'll jump into the program library. I'm going to pick out a training program
and I'm going to walk through the routines and subcategories that it comes with. And from there
I'll visit the exercise library and pull up some of the detailed instructions for individual exercises.
I'll also log my weight and my body measurements in the progress tracker so that we can see how that
data gets recorded. Lastly I'll open up the upgrade section here. I'm going to go through the
premium checkout flow and then I'm going to reload the app to confirm that my profile now shows premium
status. And it's the complete experience now from signing up as a new user to unlocking every single
feature. Alright that's a wrap on today's video. I'll catch you down here in the comments section
below. I'm always looking forward to hearing your feedback and of course thank you for spending
your time with me today and I'll definitely catch you at the next one. Thanks for watching.