Can AI help us learn?
Some of you might be thinking, of
course, it's so powerful. It can do so
many things, customize them for us. But
I want to say that the biggest
revolution AI is bringing to education.
Is not that it's going to make math more
fun for you or it's going to explain
Shakespeare like you're 5 years old. The
biggest revolution AI is bringing to
education is that it's highlighting the
systems failed incentives.
Because why should anybody study when
we've told them the whole time that all
that matters at the end isn't the
process, it's the A+.
Why should they actually put in all the
hard work to write draft after draft for
an essay when the feedback is just B?
No extra notes, nothing to motivate them
to want to learn harder.
And these companies are much faster than
our institutions. Most recently, OpenAI,
Google, Anthropic have all been giving
away their most powerful models for free
until the end of May, which as you might
guess is exactly during the time of
finals. So, we are putting these tools
completely unregulated in front of
vulnerable students right at the time
where they're most desperate to use
them.
And yet, these companies will say AI is
going to revolutionize education,
particularly through personalization.
Company after company will say that
through personalized tutoring, AI is
going to revolutionize education and
make it so much better for everyone. And
why not, right? The image of a
one-on-one tutor is so compelling.
Talking to a person, feeling this
connection, getting my education
customized just for me. It sounds
amazing.
And today, education looks like this. A
teacher in front of an army of students.
And if the technologists believe that
the ideal looks like this, one teacher,
one student, then why not just flip out
the teacher for an AI? And then the next
step is an army of AIs with an army of
students. Sounds like a perfect model of
education.
Except perfection is not what we should
strive for when it comes to learning. We
don't want engineers that studied how to
build bridges in perfect conditions
because the real world is everything but
perfect. It's full of messes.
And amidst all this noise, I don't see
any of these companies asking, "What is
this student meant to learn with AI?"
Because if the idea is to make getting
that A+ easier, then I'm not interested.
We're going to just waste 12 to 15 years
of our lives, but more efficiently now
doing exams we're not going to remember
a day after graduation.
Now, for those of you out there who are
educators like me, you might have
noticed a discrepancy between my opening
question and the follow-up statement. I
asked, "Can AI help us learn?" And I
followed it up with the biggest AI uh
the biggest revolution AI is bringing to
education.
But you might be feeling something which
is education is not learning.
Education is a is a construct, something
we as a society put our kids through.
It's a system. But learning is a skill,
a very human skill. And when we do it
correctly, magical things can happen. We
can motivate people to become their best
selves. We can motivate people to work
together and to contribute to society in
the ways that we need to most.
Now, in one of my classes, I like to sit
around with students and work in the
best way possible. I'm a university
instructor, but it was really hard to
find a bunch of 20-year-olds working
nicely together. So, I took this stock
photo of a bunch of kids
and I noticed that one of the students
had the price of her business model
because we were building uh small
businesses and selling the products. She
priced her business at $50 per month.
And so, I asked her, "Why did you price
it that?" And her answer,
that's what chat GPT said.
Now, some of you might say, you know,
obviously this is not ideal, but isn't
it very similar to what they were doing
before? Kids were just saying that's
what I saw on Google. But I I say it
depends.
It depends because on Google when used
correctly, we have all these sources to
go through, multiple perspectives that
we can look at and compare.
But what happens is the magical allure
of that first result. Everyone only
clicked on that without looking at
anything else. In this particular
question, I asked, "How can I price my
business?" And that first result is from
the BDC, an extremely reputable source,
but it's telling me how to price the
business itself, not the services of my
business. It didn't understand the
query.
Now, in Chad GPT, if you type in how
should I price my business, it actually
understands the query better. I don't
know if you can read that up there, but
it basically says there are multiple
ways to price your services. But amongst
that is a lot of baseless advice with no
sources. And that's a problem
because even though chat GPT has a
function where if you highlight
something in the text, quotation marks
appear. Some of you might not know this.
Then you can click on those quotation
marks and query that specific thing. But
if people weren't clicking on the second
result on Google, they're not going to
use the power user features in chat GPT
or any of these other AIS,
what's likely going to happen is they're
going to scroll to the bottom of the
query and they're going to type, okay,
I get it. My business is like Turboax. I
help accountants calculate people's
taxes. Tell me what number I should put
there. And of course, nobody's reading
the, you know, chat GPT might make
mistakes subtitles, right? Everyone
clicks on the uh terms of service before
you agree. Yeah. So then Chad GPT is
going to spit out an essay personalized
to the language of the person. It's
extremely compelling and despite all the
information on there, people are only
going to look at that centerpiece, which
if I zoom in is the actual random answer
of how much this person should charge
for their business.
The prompt, and this is a real prompt,
had nothing but what I had on the
screen, a small description of what the
business does. No context for who the
users is, nothing. And so the student is
participating in what's called cognitive
offloading. They're effectively
relinquishing their cognitive powers to
a machine. And you can do this with
people, too. We do it with Google when
we click on the first result without
looking at anything else. The problem is
how this is being understood.
In NYU, a professor changed their
assessment so that it could be harder
for kids to use chat GPT. And the
student replied that he is interfering
with the students learning style.
Chat GPT is not a learning style.
Now, when you combine that with
something that uh we see in technology,
so I'm a UX designer in addition to
being a university professor. And our
job as user experience designers is to
simplify the way people use technology.
But there's an byproduct from that that
arises which is called a dark pattern.
And what that means is we can simplify a
UX to the point that we might manipulate
what the user uh's intention is. And
I'll show you an example.
Take this zoo. As you're buying the
tickets and checking out, they want a
donation. We all love a zoo. It's a
charitable organization.
Now, the arrow pointing to the right,
and because we're English speakers or
French speakers, we write right, you
know, from uh from left to right. The
arrow pointing to the right is most
likely what people are going to click
on. It's dark green. It's rich. But if
you don't want to donate, you have to
click on the one that looks like it's
going to the back with the teeny tiny no
donation over there. That is a user
experience dark pattern. And when a chat
GPT or large language model like it
speaks to you in a perfect tone suited
just to keep you on the on the tool,
that is something very similar.
According to this author, when a large
language model constantly validates you
and praises you causing you to spend
more time on it, that's the same kind of
thing as a dark pattern.
And we see this already. A recent update
of chat GPT that was rolled back
fortunately
praised a user for believing a
conspiracy theory that led him to stop
taking all his medications when he had
heart palpitations and told him he is a
brave individual for taking control of
his own life for isolation and for
stopping his meds.
And it doesn't just stop at students.
Professionals
have been tested and they are at risk as
well. A researcher ran a study on over
300 uh professionals working in a large
corporation, a tech company like Google,
Microsoft, and found that when they were
tested on a variety of things, the
results were quite stunning.
Before I show you the chart, let's look
at the key here. The two shades of blue
are for much less effort and less
effort, respectively, from dark blue to
light blue. Now when tested the 319
workers uh responded to a survey that
when they used CH GPT on knowledge they
felt up to 70 like 70% of them responded
that they feel they use less effort in
their cognition. When it comes to
comprehension of what they're reading
same thing
assessment of the knowledge synthesis we
have analysis and evaluation. All of
these at least 60% of people said that
there is they they felt that they were
putting in less effort and that's
extremely potent because these AIs are
only going to get better.
The same author of this study wrote a
beautiful paper called what co-pilot
becomes autopilot and he says the risk
of moving to autopilot in is an even
greater challenge than the more commonly
discussed issue of AI hallucinations or
factual errors because the more
pernicious outcome is that generative AI
becomes complicit in intellectual
descaling and the atrophy of human
critical thinking faculties.
So today when you ask chat GPT a query,
it gives you an instant result. But in
my UX studio, me and my co-founder ran
some experiments to see if we can change
this up a little bit. For example, what
if it first clarified before it answered
asked you some clarification questions?
Or a more another example is what if it
assigned you some homework before it
actually gave you a full answer.
Between these options, there are
different levels of resistance that the
AI is uh is is offering. But what the
same author of when co-pilot becomes
autopilot advocates for is something
called productive resistance. And we
haven't yet found what that is. It's
essentially the amount of resistance an
AI should give you before you either
leave it or go to a simpler AI so that
you can do that cognitive off-roading
that is so tempting.
But how can we figure out the right
amount of productive resistance when
open AI and all these companies won't
reveal their data sets? We literally do
not know how they train their AI to this
day. When companies themselves don't
know how these AIs work, anthropic in
this example is building an MRI to
analyze how the machine they themselves
built worked. This is unprecedented in
the history of human technology. We
cannot reverse engineer these things.
The solution is likely going to lie
between both individuals and the system.
It can't be one or the other. For
individuals, we might have to learn what
we learn from fitness and nutrition. For
example, maybe we should understand what
the LMS are good for and what they're
not good for. Just like at the gym, some
exercises are better for some things
than others.
We should u practice using LLM to assist
our thinking rather than replace our
thinking. Again, you wouldn't take a
forklift to the gym, right? The point is
to do the reps.
Or maybe you want to make a habit out of
verifying that the the information that
LLMs get gives us, just like we look at
the back of uh food product when we pick
it up, the nutrition label.
On a systemic level, we need to look at
both governments and education to make
changes
on on the schooling level. At least here
in North America, I don't think that we
treat our kids with with the amount of
intelligence that they have. In Finland,
kids as young as 6 years old study myths
and disinformation.
6 years old. We do not talk to these
kids about things this complex here.
They're clearly capable.
And for governments, we need more
regulation, not less. Which is exactly
what's happening in North America. Once
again, these AIs cannot run rampant like
in the example I gave earlier, just
spreading their AI to students even
though they're in the middle of finals
when they're most vulnerable. It has to
be a cycle between individual
responsibility and responsibility from
the system.
Now, as an educator, I love the five W's
and H. There are classic for writing
essays. The questions what, why, when,
where, who, and how. And I opened with
the question, can AI help us learn? But
maybe the question should be, what can
AI help us learn? Or how can AI help us
learn?
Maybe it should be why should AI help us
learn or when and where does AI help
with learning?
But the question that scares me the most
and that I want to leave you with to
reflect on is who does AI really help
when we end up depending on learning
with it? Thank you very much.
[Music]